At the edge of the world, his journey begins.
Cast Away is a adventure, drama film directed by Robert Zemeckis.
Chuck Noland, a top international manager for FedEx, and Kelly, a Ph.D.
student, are in love and heading towards marriage.
Then Chuck's plane to Malaysia crashes at sea during a terrible storm.
He's the only survivor, and finds himself marooned on a desolate island.
With no way to escape, Chuck must find ways to survive in his new home.
Chuck Noland, played by Tom Hanks.
Kelly Frears, played by Helen Hunt.
Jerry Lovett, played by Chris Noth.
Ramon, played by Paul Sanchez.
Bettina Peterson, played by Lari White.
Fyodor, played by Leonid Citer.
Cast Away is a 2000 American survival drama film directed and
produced by Robert Zemeckis, written by William Broyles Jr.
and starring Tom Hanks, Helen Hunt, and Nick Searcy.
Hanks plays a FedEx troubleshooter who is stranded on a deserted island after his plane crashes in the
South Pacific, and the plot focuses on his desperate attempts to survive and return home.
Filming took place from January to March 1999, and April to May 2000.
Cast Away was released on December 22, 2000, by 20th Century Fox in the United States and Canada and
by DreamWorks Pictures through United International Pictures in other territories.
It grossed $429.6 million worldwide, making it the
third-highest-grossing film of 2000.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, who
praised the screenplay and Hanks's performance.
Hanks won Best Actor – Motion Picture Drama at the 58th Golden Globe Awards and was nominated
for Best Actor in a Leading Role at the 73rd Academy Awards for Cast Away.
The film explores themes of exotic island, suicide
attempt, volleyball, survival, remarriage.
The tone is emotional and intense.